<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  ~ /**
  ~  * Created by Vladimir Belov on 17.01.2024, 23:29
  ~  * Copyright (c) 2018 - 2024. All rights reserved.
  ~  * Last modified 19.09.2023, 11:17
  ~  */
  -->

<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">

    <string-array name="faq" tools:ignore="InconsistentArrays">

        <item>###Event notifications</item>

        <item>#No notifications appear</item>
        <item>The first step is to make sure that the setting \"Notification period\" has any period selected. After that try to select item \"Test notification\". If after all of the above, the notification still does not appear, then the matter is in the Android settings: either the \"Do not disturb\" mode is turned on, or all notifications are turned off in the notification manager, or the battery saving mode is turned on in the smartphone.</item>

        <item>#Multiple notifications per event</item>
        <item>Setting \"Notification period\" in the main application settings allows you to select several separate periods for notification of an event. For example, you can set up receiving notifications for the week and day of the event.</item>

        <item> </item>
        <item>###<![CDATA[<a id="widgets">Widgets]]></item>

        <item>#Widget settings</item>
        <item>To edit the settings of photo widget, click on event caption of the rightmost event. Clicking anywhere else in this event will open events list.</item>
        <item>If no suitable events were found for the widget and the notification \"Events not found\" was displayed, then clicking on message will open this widget settings.</item>
        <item>The on event click reaction may be configured in \"Settings-> Widgets (common settings)-> On click action\"</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<img src="pref_widget.png" width=100%><br>]]></item>

        <item>#Events don\'t fit or photos are too narrow</item>
        <item>Go to the widget settings and try to modify \"Custom events number\" setting.</item>

        <item>#Widgets are not updating</item>
        <item><![CDATA[You must disable battery optimization for the application. There are different settings for different Android shells: <ul>
        <li>for Xiaomi MIUI this is \"Enable Autostart\" (Security–> Permissions–> Autostart)
        <li>for pure Android 9-11 this is \"Disable Battery optimization\" (Apps and notifications-> Advanced-> Special app access-> Battery optimization)
        <li>for Huawei EMUI this is \"Enable Autostart\" (Settings-> Battery-> Start applications)</ul>]]></item>
        <item>When battery optimization is enabled, there will be a warning message at the top of the screen in each widget preference screen. A similar inscription will be at the bottom of the application settings. To turn off optimization, click on the red label</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<img src="battery_optimization_on_en.png" width=100%><br>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[Sometimes on Android 9-10 widgets stop updating after installing a new version of the app. To fix widget updates you need to:<ol>
        <li>remove the widget from the screen
        <li>clear the launcher cache (in Android settings in the list of applications find the launcher and select \"clear cache\" in properties)
        <li>restart the smartphone
        <li>re-add the widget to the screen
        </ol>]]></item>
        <item>If the standard widget update mechanism does not work, you can turn on the forced update interval: Settings-> Widgets-> Update interval.</item>

        <item>###Events</item>

        <item>#Contact events</item>
        <item>By default, events (birthdays, anniversaries, user events, other events) from all accounts on the device are shown.</item>
        <item>To restrict the choice of accounts for scanning events, it need to select the necessary ones in Settings-> Events setup-> Events sources-> Accounts.</item>
        <item>To display events from all accounts click button \"All\".</item>

        <item>#<![CDATA[<a id="events_calendar">Calendar events]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[Any calendar events from the selected calendars are supported.<ul>
         <li>If the calendar contains only one type of events, then such calendars should be selected in the appropriate section (<img src="ic_event_birthday.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Birthday, <img src="ic_event_other.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Other event).
         <li>Calendars with events of different types are specified in the section <img src="btn_zoom_page_press.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Event sources.
         <li>If you want to specify links to external resources, web links in calendar events should be in the Description field and start with http:// or https://
         <li>Depending on the selected section where the calendar is specified, the mechanism for importing events is different.
         </ul>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<img src="ic_event_birthday.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Birthday: During importing of event there is a search for a contact in the address book. Name recognition rules and name format are used for this (they are set in Settings-> Events setup-> Import settings). By default, the whole event title is used as the contact name. If a contact is found, the person\'s data is added to the event details: photo, organization, position, web links. There are three options: <ol>
        <li>contact found, but there is already data about the birthday - the date from the calendar will be added to the event (with or without a year - depending on the setting)
        <li>the contact was found, but there is no information about the birthday - a new event will be added to the list
        <li>contact not found - a new event will be added
        </ol>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<img src="ic_event_other.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Other event: these calendar events are not shown on the widgets, only in the event list and notifications. The entire event title will be used as event naming.<br>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<br><img src="btn_zoom_page_press.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Different types of events: <ul>
         <li>The event type is determined by the contents of the Description field of event. To determine the type, standard event labels and (or) your own label are used, which you need to specify for events yourself.
         <li>If the event type is not defined as Other event, a contact search will be performed by the name of the calendar event (similar to the contact search for birthdays described above).
         <li>Calendar events can be created both in the standard calendar application (simply specifying the required type in the event description) and in third-party applications. For example, when creating events in the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.withouthat.acalendar">aCalendar</a> application, you can select the event type (anniversary , wedding, birthday, etc.) and the corresponding type will be added to the Description field automatically.
         </ul>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[How to setup the display of events:<ol>
        <li>In the standard calendar application, create a calendar (or choose to display the calendar for national or religious holidays)
        <li>If the calendar is empty, create or import the required events
        <li>A link to instructions on how to upload friends\' birthdays from social networks is below
        <li>If in a birthday calendar event, the contact name occupies only part of the event name, you can define rules for name retrieval. This name will be used to search for contacts in the address book to add additional attributes: photo, organization, title, alias. Rules are configured in Settings-> Events setup-> Import settings-> Name recognition rules. For example: calendar event title \"Birthday. John Doe\", rule: \"Birthday. [name]\" (without quotes)
        <li>After creating (turning on) the calendar must be selected in one of the settings (in only one!): <ul>
                         <li>Settings-> Events setup-> Event Sources-> Calendars
                         <li>Settings-> Events setup-> Birthday-> Calendars
                         <li>Settings-> Events setup-> Other Event-> Calendars
        </ul>
        </ol>]]></item>

        <item>#<![CDATA[<a id="events_files">Events from local files]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[Events and birthdays from <a href="https://4pda.to/forum/index.php?showtopic=203976">DarkBirthday Widget</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.marcow.birthdaylist">Birthdays</a> are supported with some extra features:<ul>
        <li>event date can be of any format without spaces (DD.MM.YYYY, MM/DD/YYYY, YYYY-MM-DD etc)
        <li>if the year is unknown set 0000
        <li>the file must be saved in UTF-8 encoding
        <li>if there are several pairs of brackets after the name, then if the pairs of brackets follow each other - the content inside the last pair will be moved to contacts job title, if one pair is inside the other - the content inside the outer brackets will be moved to contacts job title
        <li>if the file only lists events of a certain type (<img src="ic_event_birthday.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Birthday, <img src="ic_event_other.webp" width=5 % style="vertical-align:middle"> Other event), such files must be specified in the settings section corresponding to their type
         <li>files with different types of events are specified in the section <img src="btn_zoom_page_press.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Event Sources. The event type is determined by the flag (below is the format and examples)
         <li>for all event types except <img src="ic_event_other.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Other event, searches for a contact in the address book to merge with duplicate events or add web links
         <li>If extra features are on it is possible to setup how to deal with events whose type could not be determined: Settings-> Events setup-> Import settings  (by default: Set as <img src="ic_event_other.webp" width=5% style=" vertical-align:middle"> Other event)
         <li>To use events from Birthdays, they must be exported to a file: Synchronization-> Save to SD card
        </ul>]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[<b><a href="https://4pda.to/forum/index.php?showtopic=203976">DarkBirthday Widget</a> event format</b> (in square brackets - optional parameters):<br>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<b></b># COMMENT<br>&lt;<b>DATE</b>&gt;[,FLAGS] &lt;<b>NAME or EVENT TITLE</b>&gt; [([ORGANIZATION,] TITLE)] [WEB LINK]<br><br>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<img src="ic_event_other.webp" width=5% style="vertical-align:middle"> Other event. Format (in square brackets - optional parameters):<br><br># COMMENT<br>&lt;<b>DATE</b>&gt;[,FLAGS] &lt;<b>EVENT TITLE</b>&gt; [WEB LINK]
        <br><br>Examples:<br>01.01.2000 John Doe (Enigma, Boss) https://enigma.com/<br>02.01.2000 Richard Roe (Enigma,)<br>03.01.0000 Friedman v. Ferguson (neighbour)<br>01.01.2022,1 Beginning of 2022<br>15.3.44,BC Yu.Caesar was killed<br>02.03.1819,Birthday Nemo (captain,)<br>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[FLAGS:<br>1 - single event, which must be shown only once (year is required)<br>BC - Before the Common Era date (year is required!)<br>Event_label - for files containing events of different types, the event type is determined by this label. If there is a space in the label, then it must be replaced with an underscore \"_\"<br>]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[<b>Events with floating dates format</b>:<br>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<b>NWW</b>[+-OFFSET]<b>.MM.YYYY</b>[,flags] <b>EVENT TITLE</b>
        <br><br>N - week number (1..5, Y - second to last, Z - last one)
        <br>WW - weekday (MO,TU,WE,TH,FR,SA,SU)
        <br>OFFSET - set by day (+ or - sign)
        <ul><li>instead of NWW, you can use the keywords "Easter", "Catholic_Easter" or "NY"
        <li>short names of the days of the week (WW), “Easter”, “NY” depend on the language of the application
        <li>if the year is not 0000, then the number of years from the beginning of the holiday will be counted
        <li>flags - described above</ul>
         <br>Examples:
         <br>2SU.02.0000 Second Sunday of February
         <br>3WE.03.1974 The third Wednesday of March, celebrated since 1974
         <br>ZSU.11.0000 Last Sunday in November
         <br>5SU.9.0000 fifth Sunday in September
         <br>1TH+1.10.0000 the next day after the first Thursday in October
         <br>3TU-10.08.0000 10 days until the third Tuesday in August
         <br>YSA.06.0000 second to last Saturday of June
         <br>NY+255.0000 Programmers Day (256th day of the year)
         <br>Easter.0000 Orthodox Easter
         <br>Easter+49.0000 Orthodox Trinity
         <br>Catholic_Easter.0000 Catholic Easter
         <br>]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[<b><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.marcow.birthdaylist">Birthdays</a> event format</b>:<br>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[❙YYYY-MM-DD❙Name❙Event type (Birthday, Anniversary, Custom)❙Event label or null❚<br><br>for example:<br> ❙1900–02–04❙John Doe❙Birthday❙null❚<br>❙2009–03–09❙John Doe❙Custom❙Death❚<br>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<br>How to setup the display of events:<ol>
        <li>Download or create file with events
        <li>Select file in settings (in only one!): <ul>
                        <li>Settings-> Events setup-> Event Sources-> Files
                        <li>Settings-> Events setup-> Birthday-> Files
                        <li>Settings-> Events setup-> Other Event-> Files
         </ul>
        </ol>]]></item>

        <item>#Importing events from social networks</item>
        <item><![CDATA[Facebook friends\' birthdays can be exported to calendar using the fb2cal tool: <a href="https://github.com/mobeigi/fb2cal">link</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UnsbV8EJ8-Y">video instructions</a>]]></item>

        <item> </item>
        <item>###Common</item>

        <item>#Search</item>
        <item><![CDATA[To search for multiple parameters, separate them with commas (any value) or \"+\" (all values), for example:<ul>
        <li>\"John, Mary\"- will display contact events with the names John or Mary
        <li>\"John+Gemini\"- will display contact events with the name John and the zodiac sign Gemini
        </ul>]]></item>
        <item>The search use all event data (to check: enable \"Extra features\" in common settings, long press on event in main list, item \"Event data\").</item>
        <item> </item>

        <item>#Application interface language</item>
        <item>If you want to help translate this application into some language close to you or if you find an inaccuracy in the translation - e-mail me (button is below).</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>